Bhekisile Jozi

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Email address | GitHub | LinkedIn | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Full-stack web developer with more than two years of experience, thriving on pair programming and remote work. Experienced in designing user-friendly websites and web applications for both desktop and mobile platforms. Fluent in multiple languages, frameworks, and technologies such as React/Redux, Ruby on Rails, and PostgreSQL. Background as a statistics tutor complements the journey into web development, cultivating strong communication and problem-solving skills. Thrives on challenges of adapting to new technologies and staying abreast of industry trends. A perpetual learner, finds joy in exploring the ever-evolving landscape of web development, constantly seeking opportunities to enhance expertise.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, HTML5, CSS3

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, PostgreSQL

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Render, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring and Problem-Solving

EXPERIENCE

Highlighted Personal Projects / Freelancer

Remote

Full Stack Web Developer

Nov 2022 - Present

Created more than 15 projects using different tech-stacks: HTML5/CSS3, JS, React/Redux, Ruby and Ruby on Rails. Some of the projects include:

• Space Travelers' Hub - is a web application designed to assist users in managing their rocket and mission reservations for space travel. Collaborated in a two-person team, focusing on developing the mission page, fetching data from APIs, and managing styling aspects.

Built with: React/Redux, CSS and Jest

Recipe App - The app will help you keep track of all your recipes and ingredients. It will allow you to save
ingredients, keep track of what you have, create recipes, and generate a shopping list based on what you have
and what you are missing from a recipe.

Built with: Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL and Bootstrap 5

• Math Magicians - It contains a built-in calculator and generates new quotes when the page loads or refreshes. Users will find it fun and interesting, especially those who like reading quotes and doing simple calculations.

Built with: React

Greenview Tutorial Centre / self-employed

Mar 2014 - Sep 2022

Data Analyst / Private Tutor

- Provided statistical support to college students, communicating complex statistical concepts clearly, resulted in 90% overall passing rate, with some students obtaining distinction and achieving excellent grades.
- Private client data analysis, advanced statistical methodologies and research, and data visualization and interpretation to their satisfaction resulted in 10% more referrals.

- Tutored statistics and financial modeling while also directing the college's performance data analysis, resulting in a 5% improvement for the college.
- Proficient in Statistics Tools: R, Python, SQL, Excel, SAS, and SPSS.

Skills include Teaching, Communication, Mentoring, and Data Analysis.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE Aug 2022 - Dec 2023

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard gitflow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

UNIVERSITY OF SOUTH AFRICA

Feb 2017 - Nov 2020

Degree, Statistics

• Thesis: The effectiveness of the job creation program and its association with unemployment, highest education, gender, and provinces using LogLinear analysis method.

CERTIFICATES (Udemy):

- Learn JavaScript: Full-Stack from Scratch
- The Ultimate React Course 2024: React, Redux and More
- Become a WordPress Developer: Unlocking Power with Code